♪ ♪
(acoustic guitar strumming)
(tuning string)
(continues tuning)
(short strum)
"I am," I said.
"I am," I cried.
I am...
...an entertainer.
When I'm not doing engine work
or oil changes,
I, uh... I'm the lead guitar
with the Dog Night Specials
at the Red Dragon Lounge.
The band ain't great,
but they serve free hot dogs
on Wednesday nights,
so there's that.
I am the only honky
in an all-Black band
called The Esquires.
Yeah, I hold my own.
So far, they haven't given me
the hook like at the Apollo.
I, uh...
I got a karaoke machine
I, uh, use for solo gigs.
I sing all types.
I got Mellencamp,
Elvis, Bon Jovi.
And, oh, for these occasions,
I have created a persona.
It's like a... it's like
a superhero of rock and roll.
I mean, I got no cape
or nothing, I got no mask,
but I got...
a bolt.
You know why I got
a lightning bolt?
'Cause they call me Lightning.
(playing jaunty rhythm)
Oh, yeah.
Lightning's a star.
Lightning is a rockin' god.
He's like Chuck Berry,
Barry Manilow
and The Beatles
all rolled into one.
Oh, yeah.
He's singing the songs
people love to hear.
The songs that people need.
The songs that I need.
(sighs)
Yeah.
The songs that I need...
to keep going.
When the, uh...
when the song's over
and the applause stops,
I'm not...
I'm not Lightning anymore.
I'm just another drunk.
Hello. My name is Mike,
and I'm an alcoholic.
OTHERS:
Hi, Mike.
And, uh, I'm happy to be here
because, uh,
today's a special day.
It's, uh...
it's my sober birthday.
Uh, 20 years off the bottle
and counting.
-(encouraging chatter)
-(strums lively rhythm)
Thank you.
-Ooh. (sniffles)
-MAN: All right.
But I got a... I got a
tradition on my sober birthday.
Uh, I sing the same song
by a great man.
A man whose songs have got me
through some sad times,
some rock bottoms, and...
(sighs)
today I get to sing
one of his songs for you.
♪ But this is not
a sad song, no ♪
♪ A sad song to sing
when you're alone ♪
♪ In a way,
it's a glad song, yeah ♪
♪ A glad song, a simple song ♪
♪ That simply seems
to makes you feel good ♪
♪ When you sing along ♪
(strumming Neil Diamond's
"Song Sung Blue")
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Everybody knows one ♪
You know the words. Come on.
(others singing along):
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Every garden grows one ♪
"Me and you are subject to..."
-(full band joins in)
-♪ Me and you are subject to ♪
♪ The blues now and then ♪
♪ But when you take the blues
and make a song ♪
♪ You sing them out again ♪
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Weeping like the willow ♪
(laughter, playful screaming)
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Sleeping on my pillow ♪
♪ Funny thing ♪
♪ But you can sing it
with a cry in your voice ♪
♪ And before you know it
get to feeling good ♪
♪ You simply got no choice. ♪
(song ends)
-♪ All of my love ♪
-(band playing "Oh Boy!")
♪ All of my kissin' ♪
♪ You don't know what
you've been a-missin' ♪
♪ Oh, boy ♪
♪ When you're with me,
oh, boy ♪
♪ The world can see that you
were meant for me ♪
♪ Stars appear
and shadows a-fallin' ♪
♪ You can hear
my heart a-callin' ♪
♪ A little bit of lovin'
makes everything right ♪
♪ I'm gonna see
my baby tonight ♪
♪ All my love,
all of my kissin' ♪
♪ You don't know what
you've been a-missin' ♪
♪ Oh, boy... ♪
Who are you supposed to be?
Oh, hey, Earl.
I thought you were in Florida
on a cruise or something.
Uh, yeah, well, I thought
you were gonna be, uh, Don Ho,
singing "Tiny Bubbles."
Yeah, I'm not gonna do that.
I'm gonna go on as Lightning.
EARL: You can't go
out there like that.
You look too much like Elvis.
I mean,
you're head-to-toe in denim
like he wore in '68 Comeback.
He wore black leather
in '68 Comeback, not denim.
Not during
the "Guitar Man" medley.
-Ah.
-He wore denim.
Uh... Oh, and you even got
a lightning bolt.
I'm Lightning.
I can't wear a bolt?
That's Elvis's logo.
"Taking care of business
in a flash."
That's me. That's my handle.
-Oh, you own that, do you?
-TCB.
All right.
I am the one and only Elvis
impersonator in all Milwaukee.
(song ends)
-(cheering)
-Thank you very much.
Comin' right back.
One thing's for sure, we got
too many Elvis impersonators
and not one Little Richard.
Say it loud. (laughs)
Where's the Hawaiian shirt?
You're singing "Tiny Bubbles."
I don't want to sing
"Tiny Bubbles."
I'm gonna sing
"Eye of the Tiger,"
and then I'll close out
with "Suspicious Minds."
Over my dead body does he sing
"Suspicious Minds."
Earl, Earl, Earl, calm down.
Mike.
-MIKE: What?
-We're impersonators here.
That's why the state fair
booked us
-for the blue-haired crowd.
-(Mike sighs)
I don't look like Don Ho.
I'm not Hawaiian. It's dumb.
That's why Carl Kahananui
was doing it,
but his gallbladder ruptured.
You agreed to fill in
and do me a favor.
So you're saying no Lightning?
It's Don Ho or a no-go?
Yeah, Mike.
That's what I'm saying.
Then it's a no-go.
(sighs) Claire, you're up next.
Uh, Babs, uh, instead of
"Don't Rain on My Parade,"
do "People Who Need People."
The blue-hairs are losing
their slow dance song
since "Tiny Bubbles" is out.
BABS:
I'll manage...
I guess.
Thanks, Mike.
Sex Machine, you close it out.
-I'll go tell the band.
-All right.
(indistinct chatter, laughter)
MIKE: You supposed to be
Loretta Lynn?
Oh, oh, Patsy Cline.
I sing her songs all the time.
I don't usually
dress like this,
but any chance to sing,
you know?
Yeah, I just can't be Don Ho
on my birthday.
Oh, happy birthday.
It's not really my birthday.
Oh, o... okay.
You know, you could be
Frank Sinatra.
Maybe sing "Luck Be a Lady."
Yeah, I like Frank,
but the whole crooner vibe?
I don't know, I like to move.
-I like to rock.
-Yeah.
EARL:
Elvis has left the building.
Oh, you know who
you'd be perfect for?
Neil Diamond.
Oh, no. Never.
No, I hold that man
in such high regard.
-No, no, no, no.
-"Sweet Caroline."
-Yeah. "Ba-ba." I know, I know.
-♪ Bom, bom, bom. ♪
No, no, no, listen.
He's got other songs, too, okay?
And if it ever got back
to him that I was
goofing on his music or...
like Earl over there,
I'd kill myself.
Not Neil. I...
You know how much he got paid
for that cruise?
20,000 bucks.
That poseur pulled in 20 Gs?
-Wa-ha!
-(laughter)
Nostalgia pays.
(sighs): Oh, God,
I'm burning up in this wig.
If my boobs were just
a bit bigger, I could be Dolly.
You're a blonde?
Oh, boy, am I.
MARK: All right,
put your hands together
for Ms. Patsy
and The Greatest Hits.
I hope you sing
as good as you look.
(band playing Patsy Cline's
"Walkin' After Midnight")
(cheering)
♪ I go out walkin' ♪
♪ After midnight ♪
♪ Out in the moonlight ♪
♪ Just like we used to do ♪
♪ I'm always walkin' ♪
♪ After midnight ♪
♪ Searchin' for you... ♪
Claire Stengl.
She sing country, rock,
classical like that
"Ave Maria" joint.
MIKE:
Hmm.
She look all kind of good,
don't she?
-Huh! Yeah!
-(Mike chuckling)
My man Lightning.
♪ After midnight ♪
♪ Searchin' for you ♪
♪ I stop and see
a weepin' willow ♪
♪ Cryin' on his pillow ♪
♪ Maybe he's cryin' for me ♪
♪ And as the skies turn gloomy ♪
♪ Night winds whisper to me ♪
♪ I'm lonesome as I can be ♪
♪ I go out walkin' ♪
♪ After midnight ♪
♪ Out in the starlight ♪
♪ Just hopin' you may be ♪
♪ Somewhere a-walkin' ♪
♪ After midnight ♪
♪ Searchin' for me. ♪
-(song ends)
-DR. DAVE: Okay, Mike.
Open wide.
Geez.
You could park a car
in that gap.
I'll take a Cadillac.
I got something
much better for you.
Take a look...
at this.
Is that a lightning bolt?
Lightning for Lightning.
So when I smile,
it'll be like I'm advertising.
That is smart, Dr. Dave.
See, that is why
you're my manager, Dr. Dave.
Always thinking.
I got a call from Walter
over at First National.
First thing,
he still wants you to perform
at his Christmas party.
-Great.
-Second thing,
you're three months behind
on your mortgage.
Can't he just take it out
of my performance fee?
Mike, it's not something
you can just sing away.
Maybe you should think
about downsizing.
No, I got to keep my house.
When my daughter comes up,
that's the one consistent thing
that she's got.
Anyway, we shouldn't be talking
about downsizing.
We should be talking about
getting higher-paid gigs,
like a residency,
something steady.
Why don't you talk
to your Buddy Holly friend?
You know, he's got that gig
over at the Shawano Casino.
Eh, Mark's pissed at me.
I quit the Legends gig
the other night.
What? Why'd you quit?
'Cause he wouldn't let me
be Lightning.
You were supposed to be Don Ho.
Why I got to be
anybody other than me?
I should be enough.
Shit. Well...
I guess there goes
my ten-dollar commission.
Do you need an oil change?
Come on, give me your car keys.
(jet engine roaring)
(whistling softly)
("Cracklin' Rosie"
by Neil Diamond playing)
♪ Ah, Cracklin' Rosie,
get on board ♪
♪ Get on board ♪
♪ We're gonna ride till
there ain't no more to go ♪
-♪ Takin' it slow ♪
-♪ And Lord, don't you know ♪
-♪ Lord, don't you know ♪
-♪ We'll have me a time ♪
-♪ Don't you know ♪
-♪ With a poor man's lady ♪
-♪ Don't you know... lady ♪
(singing along):
♪ Hitchin' on a twilight train ♪
♪ Ain't nothing here
that I care to take along ♪
♪ Maybe a song ♪
♪ To sing when I want ♪
♪ No need to say please
to no man for a happy tune ♪
♪ Oh, I love my Rosie child ♪
♪ You got the way
to make me happy ♪
♪ You and me, we go in style ♪
♪ Cracklin' Rose,
you're a store-bought woman ♪
♪ But you make me sing
like a guitar hummin' ♪
♪ So hang on to me, girl ♪
♪ Our song keeps runnin' on ♪
♪ Play it now, play it now ♪
♪ Play it now, my baby... ♪
Oh! Ow! Ow!
Geez... Ow!
-(groans)
-(song continues in background)
(inhales sharply, exhales)
(breathing deeply)
("Get on Up" by The Esquires
playing)
SINGER:
Everybody!
Come on!
(vocalizing in harmony)
(crowd cheering)
-♪ Gotta get on up ♪
-♪ Get on up ♪
♪ Gotta get on up ♪
-♪ Gotta get on up now ♪
-♪ Get on up ♪
-♪ Gotta get on up ♪
-♪ How can you sit yourself ♪
♪ Down for a rest ♪
♪ When you know that
I'm trying my best ♪
♪ To dance with you? ♪
♪ Get on up ♪
-♪ To dance with you ♪
-♪ Get on up ♪
-♪ You know what, sugar? ♪
-(whooping)
(singers vocalizing in harmony)
(laughs)
-♪ Hey, you. ♪
-(song ends)
CLAIRE:
Thank you.
So...
you just go by Claire Stengl?
Well, I used to be
Claire Cartwright,
but then after the divorce,
I switched it back
to my maiden name,
which is Stengl,
so Claire Stengl.
It's not the most exciting
stage name...
I know, but it's not like
I'm Cher or Madonna.
Oh. You're better
than them broads.
(laughs)
-Stop. You're so sweet.
-You are.
I'm a hairdresser part-time.
I wash. I trim. No dye jobs.
By the way, I did change
my hair up a little bit.
-I noticed.
-Did you notice?
You also got a new tooth.
Oh, yeah. Look.
-Huh?
-Is that a lightning bolt?
-Oh, my God.
-Yes, yes, 'cause...
-'Cause you're Lightning.
-Right.
I know, I know.
I know all about you.
My girlfriends and I,
we used to go to Hegarty's
-on Friday nights.
-Hegarty's. Come on.
And I remember you sang ZZ Top,
"Sharp Dressed Man,"
and at the chorus you'd, like,
push your pelvis out like Elvis
and we'd scream
like schoolgirls.
You're really good.
You know the other day
when I said it was my birthday?
Oh, yeah, the birthday
that wasn't your birthday.
What was that?
I'm an alcoholic.
-Okay.
-Not anymore.
I mean, I'm always gonna be
an alcoholic,
but I've been sober 20 years,
and the other day was...
well, they call it
a sober birthday.
Happy belated sober birthday.
Here's the thing.
With sobriety, you-you got to
face up to certain truths.
Way to go, Lightning. 20 years.
All right, I'm not a songwriter,
I'm not a sex symbol, but I
just want to entertain people
-and I want to make a living.
-I know. Me, too.
I don't want to be
a hairdresser.
I want to sing. I want to dance.
I want a house. I want a garden.
-I want a cat.
-So here's what I'm thinking.
I need a hook.
I need something big.
I need something new.
And as you put it,
nostalgia pays.
Us, me, you--
it's not going to happen.
(chuckles) Miss Fine,
you're old enough to be my...
-Watch it.
-Sister.
(audience laughing over TV)
-Hey.
-DANA: Hey, Mom.
Was the guy a wacko?
Dana, this is Mike.
Mike Sardina.
As you were.
CLAIRE:
Hi.
So, feel free
to make yourself a...
any nonalcoholic beverage
you like.
All right. (sighs)
I'm gonna make a pot of coffee.
-You like it black or sweet?
-I don't drink coffee.
-Want to start?
-(knocking)
Hi. Is Grandma down?
-Like, hours ago.
-Oh, good.
You didn't bring him home,
did you?
-Am I shiny?
-He-he's here?
'Cause I am sweating
like a whore in church.
Oh, my...
The building manager came by.
You know, we got
a two-week extension,
-but it's another $50...
-Rachel, Rachel.
Don't worry about it, okay?
I'm gonna take care of that.
-Wait...
-I'm gonna wear these.
-Those are my shoes, Mom.
-Honey, he was so cute.
-What are you...
-He was so cute on that stage
with The Esquires,
and he was smiling at me.
-Okay.
-And then we went for a walk,
and it was just magic.
And I know you see magic
all the time
'cause you're young,
but I don't.
And so it was just beautiful.
Magic doesn't happen for me
all the time.
Rachel, I want you to go
introduce yourself to him.
-Okay? I want you to do that.
-Uh, um, I'm not doing...
Rachel, don't be a sourpuss.
You're gonna go outside,
and I want you
to say hello to him.
-No, I'm not.
-No, no, no.
-We're not doing that. No, no.
-I... Mom!
I'm not doing this right now.
I have to deal with
your boyfriends all the time.
-They come into this house...
-All the time?
Yeah, the last one
smelled like a skunk.
-He was clearly a dope dealer.
-He just liked...
-No, he was not.
-He was. Yes.
-We're gonna go outside...
-He's a Zen guy, Mom.
One second. Let's go.
-Mom.
-Yeah, come on. Let's go.
-Mike? Mike.
-MIKE: Hey.
Yeah?
Mike, this is
my daughter Rachel.
Oh, hey. How's it going?
Rachel, say something.
Don't make a mess on the couch.
-Rachel!
-What?
(door closing)
Hey, what do you think?
(laughing):
Oh.
It's good.
-Right? -You know, we just got
to work your hair
a little differently,
and I got a guy for that.
All right. Oh, and look at
these outfits. Come on.
Look at that. It's, like,
shimmering, you know?
Oh. You know, my hair guy
does clothes, too.
Awesome. You know, Neil...
is special,
and I just want everyone
to get that feeling I get
when I listen
to "America" and
"Forever in Blue Jeans"...
-Or "Sweet Caroline."
-And "Sweet Caroline," yeah,
but I-I'm never gonna be
the real McCoy.
I mean, I-I don't really
look like Neil.
I don't even really
sound like Neil.
And I... I got to be Neil,
but I just got to be me, too.
Yeah, you don't want to be
a Neil Diamond... impersonator.
You want to be
a Neil Diamond interpreter.
I was looking for
the right way to say it,
and you just came right out
and said it.
A Neil Diamond interpreter.
-Mm, yeah.
-Yeah. Oh.
And you can sing
some Patsy Cline songs,
-like-like one or two.
-Oh. (scoffs)
I mean, maybe while you're
doing a costume change, but...
no, I don't want
to confuse people.
I will back you up
in keyboards and vocals,
but this is about Neil.
And this is about
his fans, you know?
Yeah. Yeah.
I can sing
the Barbra Streisand part on
-"You Don't Bring Me Flowers."
Right, but we got to get 'em
on their feet
and get 'em clapping.
-Look up "Cherry, Cherry."
-Mm.
♪ ♪
(playing Neil Diamond's
"Cherry, Cherry")
MIKE:
All right, ready?
-Two, three, and...
-(stops playing piano)
(strumming intro
to "Cherry, Cherry")
(clapping rhythmically)
♪ Baby loves me ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, she does ♪
Uh, you see where
I underlined there?
I was thinking maybe
at the top...
Oh, yeah, I double up.
I got it, I got it, I got it.
(strumming intro)
(harmonizing):
♪ Baby loves me ♪
-♪ Yeah, yeah, she does ♪
-(holding note)
Good.
♪ Ah, the girl's
outta sight, yeah ♪
♪ Says she loves me ♪
-♪ Yes, yes, she does ♪
-(holding note)
Nice.
♪ Mm, gonna show me
tonight, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, she got the way
to move me ♪
♪ Cherry ♪
♪ She got the way to groove me ♪
♪ She got the way to move me ♪
-♪ Cherry, baby ♪
-♪ She got the way ♪
♪ To groove me ♪
MIKE:
Yes. Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
♪ Tell your mama, girl,
we can't stay long ♪
♪ We got things
we gotta catch up on ♪
(Claire scatting)
♪ Mm, you know ♪
-♪ You know what I'm sayin' ♪
-Excuse me. Excuse me!
-(scatting)
-Oh.
Much too late for anyone
to be singing that loud.
CLAIRE: Ma, this is the man
I was telling you about.
Mike Sardina.
-This is Lightning.
-How you doing tonight?
Not good.
Sing softer.
(Claire sighs)
She's going
to a retirement home.
I'd like to say that
she's less grumpy in the day,
-but I'd be lying.
-(Mike laughs)
(Mike playing gentle intro
to Neil Diamond's "Play Me")
What's that? That's very pretty.
Well, she said, "Sing softer."
I'm going softer.
♪ She was morning ♪
♪ And I was nighttime ♪
♪ I one day woke up ♪
♪ To find her lying ♪
♪ Beside my bed ♪
♪ I softly said ♪
♪ "Come take me" ♪
-♪ For I've been lonely ♪
-(electronic beat playing)
♪ In need of someone ♪
♪ As though I'd done
someone wrong somewhere ♪
♪ But I don't know where ♪
(plays chord
with organ-like tone)
-♪ I don't know where ♪
-(plays electric piano tone)
♪ Come lately ♪
-(plays soft synth tone)
-♪ You are the sun ♪
♪ I am the moon ♪
♪ You are the words,
I am the tune ♪
♪ Play me ♪
(continues playing
with soft synth tone)
Nice.
♪ Song she sang to me ♪
♪ Song she brang to me ♪
♪ Words that rang in me ♪
♪ A rhyme that sprang from me ♪
♪ Warmed the night ♪
♪ And what was right ♪
♪ Became me ♪
(harmonizing):
♪ You are the sun ♪
♪ I am the moon ♪
♪ You are the words,
I am the tune ♪
♪ Play me ♪
(bell ringing)
CLAIRE:
My ex-husband?
He's a good guy.
("Play Me" continues)
And he really liked
my singing and all,
but when I started trying
to book gigs,
he just started
making fun of it,
like it was a threat
or something.
I don't know why he...
wanted to make me feel
so small, but he sure did.
-MIKE: Hmm.
-(Claire sighs)
I got to say,
with me and my ex...
...I was the one
making her feel small.
I was selfish. I was angry.
I was... wrong.
But I'm here, you know,
trying to be better.
I mean, aren't we all?
♪ And so it was ♪
♪ That I came to travel ♪
♪ Upon a road ♪
♪ That was thorned and narrow ♪
♪ Another place ♪
♪ Another grace ♪
♪ Would save me ♪
♪ You are the sun,
I am the moon ♪
♪ You are the words,
I am the tune ♪
♪ Play me ♪
♪ You are the sun,
I am the moon ♪
♪ You are the words ♪
♪ I am the tune ♪
♪ Play... ♪
♪ Me. ♪
That's great.
(plays concluding notes
on guitar)
(laughing)
And, uh, hey,
I was thinking, uh...
Yeah?
I was thinking we should
call ourselves something.
-Oh, like a tribute band name?
-Yeah.
So I'm thinking
Lightning & Thunder:
A Neil Diamond Experience.
-Lightning & Thunder?
-Yeah.
So you'd be Lightning and...
I'd be Thunder?
Uh, yeah.
You...
Mm. That is not
very professional of me,
but I've been wanting to do it
for, like, a whole...
(band playing
Buddy Holly's "Everyday")
CLAIRE:
Mm.
-Okay. I'm...
-Okay. Yeah.
(Mike grunts)
MARK:
♪ Every day ♪
♪ It's a-gettin' closer ♪
♪ Going faster
than a roller coaster ♪
♪ Love like yours will
surely come my way ♪
♪ A-hey, a-hey, hey ♪
♪ Every day seems
a little longer ♪
-♪ Every way ♪
-(coins clinking)
♪ Love's a little stronger ♪
♪ Come what may,
do you ever long for ♪
♪ True love from me? ♪
♪ Every day ♪
♪ It's a-gettin' closer ♪
♪ Going faster
than a roller coaster ♪
♪ Love like yours will
surely come my way. ♪
(song ends)
MIKE:
I know I let you down.
But just know that I am very...
Oh, what's the word you said?
"Contrary"?
-"Contrite."
-MIKE: Contrite.
He's very contrite.
There's always that one friend
you can't say no to
even though they repeatedly
crap on you.
I hope I'm that friend.
-Hey, Tom.
-(Mike sighs)
DR. DAVE:
Okay, now, Tom is a good guy.
Okay?
He's got all the connections
to all the casinos and venues
from Chicago to Branson.
-(Tom coughs)
-MARK: Mike, meet Tom D'Amato.
How are you, Mr. Sardina?
I'm huge.
(both laughing)
Uh, uh, you may not
remember this,
but-but I would sit at the bar
at the Chubby Bear...
-Oh, yeah.
-Yeah.
Every Thursday night,
and watch you play
with your first band,
-Positive Traction. Yeah.
-Positive Traction.
Yeah, we made some noise,
but it was in tune.
You were really good, Mike.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Really good band.
Well, I was, uh,
talking to your manager,
and he said that you're gonna
do a Neil Diamond show?
Mm-mm. Mm-mm.
A Neil Diamond Experience.
My partner Claire and I,
we start rehearsing
with costumes and everything
next week.
Oh. Costumes? Really?
-Wow, wow, wow.
-Right, but one day, I see us
being backed by a big
orchestra, maybe even a choir.
And I tell you,
I tell you, it's gon...
I mean, I know
we got to start small, right,
if I want to play someplace
like this, but one day...
But you got to make sure
you play "Sweet Caroline."
Oh, we close with
"Sweet Caroline."
-Oh, great.
-But we open...
with "Soolaimon."
♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
♪ Soolai, soolai, soolaimon ♪
(whispers):
A bit louder.
♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
♪ Soolai, soolai, soolaimon ♪
A little bit of smoke.
♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
-Come on, now.
-(Tom humming)
♪ Soolai, soolai ♪
♪ Soolaimon. ♪
"Soola-mond"?
-"Soolaimon." "Soolaimon."
-TOM: Uh, okay. (stammers)
Is that an African word?
Like, Swahili?
I think it might be Hebrew,
like Solomon.
No, no, it's Arabic.
It's a call to celebration.
The audience are our flock,
-and we are the shepherd.
-TOM (gasping): Oh.
-I-I just got some chills. Wow.
-You feel that? You feel it?
We're gonna get that
casino gig for you.
But it's gonna take building
a lot of momentum.
Right.
But, Mike, you have passion.
And all I ask--
if you'll allow me
to work in service
of that passion.
(chuckles softly)
-We'd love to have you
on the team. -Oh!
Music to my ears.
-Mike, thank you. (laughs)
-(Mike laughing)
-Welcome aboard.
-TOM: Thank you so much.
I have to roll right now. Sorry.
-But we will be in touch.
-(Mike laughs)
Ladies and gentlemen,
I hope you had a great time
at the Shawano Casino.
The Badger Bus will be leaving
in ten minutes
for the Potawatomi
Hotel and Casino.
See you, Mike.
All aboard!
♪ ♪
I don't know how long
this rehearsal's gonna take.
I don't want anyone
asking me that.
We really have
to call him Lightning?
-It's kind of weird.
-(sighs)
Every time he comes
to pick me up,
he tries to connect with you,
and you do not
make it easy, Rach.
He's very nervous
about you coming.
-Okay. -So to make you
more comfortable,
he invited his daughter.
-What?
-And she's your age.
-This is a playdate?
-Yeah, she's only a year older.
-Oh, Jesus Christ.
-God, why does everything
-have to be so hard?
-What am I, six?
I just want to sing and be
happy and feel loved, and I...
and I don't want everything
to be such a big deal!
(house door opens)
Come on. Come on out.
Hey.
Wave. Wave to him.
CLAIRE:
Hi!
Smile and wave at him.
Goddamn it.
Be nice.
(Angelina chuckles)
When my dad bought this place,
the runway wasn't finished.
Now you get like...
ten planes a day.
-Oh.
-Except Sundays.
So...
do you split your time
between your...
your mom and your dad?
Um...
not really.
No, I mean, my dad's cool,
but it's just...
No, I get it.
It's better for me
to be full-time with my mom
in Florida, but...
Don't get me wrong,
my dad's great.
He's just, uh... (chuckles)
He's... he's artistic.
-(chuckles)
-Mm. Artistic.
Yeah, I...
I know all about that.
Hey, Mike,
can you open the garage?
It's getting really hot in here.
I would.
The lady across the street
was giving me the evil eye
as we was unpacking the drums,
so maybe not.
Bomar.
We still good with that
barter situation we discussed
with me, uh, playing
with The Esquires?
You'd be playing four free gigs
just for all of us
to do one show.
Yeah, I understand.
It's just I, you know,
can't pay you anything
right now. That's all.
We came here for you, brother.
But your lady ain't wrong.
It's hot as Satan's balls.
Open the door.
Yeah. (sighs)
All right,
maybe just for a little bit.
(musicians practicing,
tuning instruments)
(indistinct chatter)
Mark.
What are you doing here?
Buddy Holly died at 22.
I'm 52, and I've been
keeping that guy alive
30 years past his prime.
I don't even need these.
What I'm saying is...
I'm here if you need me.
Thanks.
I didn't bring an amp.
Yeah. We got you.
All right, guys...
My dad, he was a tunnel rat
in Vietnam.
They would send him
into the tunnels underground
where the enemy was hiding,
and they had it
booby-trapped, so...
sometimes he'd have to...
like, crawl over dead bodies.
So, yeah, he...
he used to drink.
My mom, she can get,
um, depressed,
so she's, like, on meds.
I try to keep up with it
for her, 'cause she can get...
...scattered, you know?
Well, you know,
most recovering alcoholics
just trade one addiction
for another,
and music's that for Dad.
Without music, he can get, um...
(chuckles) What'd you call it?
BOTH:
Scattered.
(laughing):
Yeah.
Yeah. I think we covered all
our fucked-up family history.
-Most of it.
-(laughs)
-Might be a little more.
-Oh, there's more?
Maybe a little. Just a little.
Hey, listen, I know
we just met, too, but, um...
I have a joint.
You know, I thought
I smelled it on you.
(laughs)
(playing Neil Diamond's
"Crunchy Granola Suite")
♪ Mm ♪
♪ I got a song been on my mind ♪
♪ And the tune can be sung
and the words all rhyme ♪
(scatting in harmony)
♪ Though it don't say much
and it won't offend ♪
♪ If you sing it at school ♪
♪ They're liable
to send you home ♪
♪ Never knowin'
what you're showin' ♪
♪ Think you're growin'
your own tea ♪
♪ Good Lordy ♪
♪ Let me hear that,
get me near that ♪
♪ Crunchy Granola Suite ♪
♪ Drop your shrink
and stop your drinkin' ♪
♪ Crunchy granola's neat ♪
♪ Sing it out ♪
♪ All right ♪
I wouldn't go any shorter
than this, though.
No, I want it to ripple and wave
when the wind blows my shirt,
like... (blows sharply)
-Wind in a bar? How?
-Yeah.
Like a leaf blower.
(blows sharply)
-Do you have one?
-Sure.
♪ I know a man was outta touch ♪
♪ And he'd hide in a house
and he didn't say much ♪
(scatting in harmony)
(panting):
Okay.
I used to do this as a kid.
Come on.
Am I getting... getting on here?
-Okay. (grunts)
-Here.
ANGELINA:
Lay back.
(both laughing)
♪ Family man ♪
♪ Tried my brand ♪
♪ Dig! Ha! ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Let me hear that,
get me near that ♪
♪ Crunchy Granola Suite ♪
♪ Drop your shrink
and stop your drinkin' ♪
♪ Crunchy granola's neat ♪
♪ Sing it out ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ Hey! Come on! Hey! ♪
-(hollers)
-♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah. ♪
Whoo! (laughs)
(laughing)
-Yeah!
-(laughter, excited chatter)
Oh, I was scared
you were gonna hit your head.
(laughter)
(laughter echoes, fades)
If you live long enough...
(chuckles)
you can see your dreams
die a slow death.
Young people don't know
how good they have it.
Not 'cause they can, uh,
touch their toes
and screw all night.
They haven't learned that most
things just don't work out.
♪ ♪
Most times, you just mess it up,
so it's easier not to try.
We're all just looking
for some hope.
But at my age, hope is hard.
(chuckles)
Hope's not enough.
(engine sputtering)
(groaning)
(pained grunting)
(gasping breaths)
(panting)
GROUP:
God, grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change,
the courage to change
the things I can,
and the wisdom
to know the difference.
(continues panting)
(engine starts)
(engines roaring)
There seems to be a bit
of a miscommunication.
(beeps)
When I booked this gig
a month ago,
it was my understanding
that there was
a motor home convention in town,
being that
that's what I was told.
No, I didn't.
I did not say that.
You said the
Emerald Motor Home Convention!
I said
Emerald Lion Motor Club Reunion.
And you said you had
a classic rock band
like ZZ Top or CCR.
-Neil Diamond? Not classic?
-MIKE: All right, Tom, Tom,
Tom, Tom, Tom.
(chuckling): Tom,
I still don't see the problem.
You see, Mike,
with these motor home types,
uh, I figured we're
in the pocket, you know?
-But these bikers...
-MIKE: They love Neil Diamond.
I-I don't know. Look at 'em.
They got leather, chains. I-I...
Neil Diamond doesn't
have chains.
MARK:
That's a lot of leather.
We ain't got nothing
these hog-squashers can dig.
Mike, why don't we put
Claire up first?
I mean, look at her.
She's pretty. She's nice.
Have her sing "Crazy" or one
of those Lynyrd Skynyrd songs.
-They'd love Lynyrd Skynyrd.
-CLAIRE: You know, I can fake
my way through
"Sweet Home Alabama."
No, no, no, we're not changing
our show, all right? No.
TOM: At least start
with "Sweet Caroline."
Nobody here is gonna appreciate
the Arabic incantations
of "Solomon."
-"Soolaimon"!
-"Soolaimon."
We could move up
"Kentucky Woman."
And open with "America."
-"America" is great.
-'Cause bikers love...
I'm in charge of this band,
and I'm telling you
we open with "Soolaimon"!
Have you got the fans?
Yeah.
I got the fans.
(band playing "Soolaimon")
(crowd chattering)
CLAIRE:
♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
Travelers of our nation's
Emerald highway,
-welcome to Tierney's Tavern.
-♪ Soolai, soolai, soolaimon ♪
-I am Lightning.
-♪ Soo... ♪
This vision of beauty
is Thunder.
-Oh, come on.
-(laughter)
We bring greetings
to the great city of Chicago
with the songs
of the incomparable,
leather-jacket-wearing
entertainer Neil Diamond.
We are Lightning & Thunder.
♪ ♪
♪ God of my want, want, want ♪
♪ Lord of my need, need, need ♪
♪ Leading me on ♪
-Man, what is this trash?
-♪ On, on ♪
♪ On to my woman,
she dance for the sun ♪
♪ Lord of my day, day, day ♪
WOMAN:
I'm blinded by that shirt!
Play "Free Bird"!
-♪ God of my night ♪
-MAN 2: This is awful!
♪ Night, night ♪
WOMAN:
You're ruining my night!
-♪ Seek for the way, way, way ♪
-(indistinct shouting)
-♪ Taking me home ♪
-Someone get him off there.
MAN 3: What does bumblebee
think he's doing?
-♪ She callin' ♪
-MAN 4: Nice shirt, loser!
-♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
-MAN 5: Get off the stage!
MAN 6:
Play some rock and roll!
-♪ Soolai, soolai ♪
-WOMAN: My mom sings better!
♪ Soolaimon ♪
-♪ Soo... ♪
-(music stops)
-(raucous shouting)
-MIKE: Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Come on.
-Hey, come on.
-All right, that's enough.
-Get rid of the guy.
-MIKE: Just, we're up here.
We're just trying
to entertain you. That's all.
Neil Diamond sucks!
(bikers cheering)
What did you say?
You heard me, nelly.
(scattered laughter)
Oh, Mike! Oh, my God!
-Jimmy, get over there!
-CLAIRE: Oh, my God, Mike!
-MARK: Mike!
-Mike! Oh, my God.
-Come on, say it again!
-Come on, nelly!
You're the worst manager
in the history of the world.
Don't talk to me. Don't talk!
What did you say? Say it again!
TOM:
Mike!
(both muttering, grunting)
CLAIRE:
Oh, Tom. Here.
Ah, it's okay. I-I'm a bleeder.
Oh, God.
-It's really...
-I mean, it's just a nosebleed.
It's not bad.
Hey, Tom, can you drive?
Because if you can't,
one of us could.
No, I-I have to, Ricky.
It's a liability
insurance issue.
You know, it's a requirement.
Tom, put this in your nose.
-This?
-Yeah, to...
Hold it in there
so the blood doesn't come out.
MAN:
Yeah, let it all down the side.
TOM:
Tell Mike I'm sorry.
-CLAIRE: You be safe.
-(Tom sighs)
TOM:
Okay.
(dog barking in distance)
(bus engine starts)
(horn honking)
Had a whole plan for how
tonight would go, and I just...
it all went south.
Well, you made it very clear
that you are in charge of this
band and make the decisions,
so I guess if it was
a Donna Summer tribute band,
I'd be calling the shots, but...
now I know.
It's your show.
I mean, would it have killed you
-to open with "Sweet Caroline"?
-(sighs)
There's more to Neil Diamond
than "Sweet Caroline."
He's got hundreds of songs,
and all anybody wants to hear
is "Sweet Caroline"--
"bom, bom, bom."
That's right.
That's what they want to hear.
After the show, I was gonna
take you to this fancy hotel
with a big suite
and an all-you-can-eat buffet,
and I was gonna propose and...
What?
Yeah, I got you
a ring and everything.
But if you're not into it,
maybe we could still
hit that buffet.
They got a guy there that does
omelets and crepes and...
CLAIRE:
Mmm!
(laughing):
Oh, yes!
-Oh, yes!
-(laughing): What?
To you, to this, to everything.
-Okay.
-(laughs)
Oh.
Okay, wait, one thing.
Anything.
We open with "Sweet Caroline."
-Agree?
-I do.
(band playing Neil Diamond's
"Sweet Caroline")
MIKE:
♪ Where it began ♪
(cameras clicking)
♪ I can't begin
to know when... ♪
SEX MACHINE:
I would like to welcome you
to this celebration of marriage.
Marriage is the promise
between two people
-who love each other...
-(snickering)
...who trust that love,
honor each other as individuals
in that togetherness,
and who wish to spend the rest
of their lives together.
...keeping yourself
solely unto him
as for as long as you may live?
I do.
♪ Hands... ♪
SEX MACHINE: ...and the power
entrusted in me,
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
Now, jump back
and kiss yourself.
(laughter)
-♪ Touching me ♪
-(cheering)
♪ Touching you ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
ALL:
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
MIKE: ♪ Good times never
seemed so good ♪
♪ I've been inclined ♪
-♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
-♪ To believe ♪
♪ They never would, but now I ♪
We need to hit two venues
in under four hours.
We got a 7:00 p.m. show
at Good Time Charlie's...
All right, here we go.
All aboard!
♪ Look at the night ♪
♪ And it don't seem so lonely ♪
♪ We fill it up with only two ♪
♪ And when I hurt ♪
♪ Hurtin' runs off
my shoulders ♪
♪ How can I hurt
when holding you? ♪
Are you ready to rock out
to some Neil Diamond?
-(cheering)
-♪ Warm ♪
♪ Touching warm ♪
♪ Reaching out ♪
♪ Touching me ♪
♪ Touching you ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Good times never
seemed so good ♪
♪ So good, so good, so good ♪
♪ I've been inclined ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ To believe they never would ♪
♪ Oh, no, no ♪
Oh, my heart throbs.
He's such a good-looking man.
Claire Sardina sang
Patsy Cline songs.
Mike Sardina sang
rock and roll medleys.
But together, they are
Lightning & Thunder,
a Neil Diamond tribute band
the people of Milwaukee
can't seem to get enough of.
I just love
Lightning & Thunder.
They are my fave.
TOM:
You know, you're gonna see
Lightning & Thunder
in Las Vegas.
Oh, "Sweet Caroline"? I-I think
that's my new favorite song.
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Good times never
seemed so good ♪
♪ So good, so good, so good ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ I believe they never could ♪
♪ Oh, no, no. ♪
(cheering and applause)
(song ends)
Here's the question:
Tell me something
that people are struck by.
-Lightning.
-Oh! Lightning!
-Yeah.
-Lightning.
Lightning!
-(bell dings)
-(crowd cheering)
(shouts excitedly, laughs)
-(grunts fiercely)
-Oh, no.
Rachel, can you please
make me spaghetti?
Mom wants fish sticks again.
I'm dying.
-Mike?
-MIKE (laughing): Yeah!
-Eddie on the phone for you.
-MIKE: My show, baby.
Uh, auto shop Eddie
or another Eddie?
-No clue.
-MIKE: As you were.
-CLAIRE: Number one: lightning.
-RACHEL (laughs): Really?
-CLAIRE: Yeah.
-What?
-(snapping fingers)
-(hushed): Hey. Hey.
CONTESTANT (over TV):
Another person.
MIKE: Uh, you mean like
a commercial or...
I mean, we've done car shows
before, but never a...
(TV muted)
Like a concert for jelly?
Hold on. What's a Pearl Jam?
-What about Pearl Jam?
-That's what I'm asking.
This guy says
he's with Pearl Jam.
Give me the phone.
Who the hell is this?
What's Pearl Jam?
It's a band, Mike.
You don't know who Pearl Jam is?
Oh, Pearl Jam's a "who"?
RACHEL:
C-Could you hold, please?
Yeah, so...
um... I think I'm gonna
throw up right now.
(laughing):
This is Eddie Vedder.
Eddie Vedder's on the phone
right now.
Say something and not stupid.
(laughs)
(Mike clears throat)
Yeah, Lightning speaking.
Uh, all right, let me check.
Are we doing anything on Friday?
ALL:
No!
Um... (clears throat)
no, it sounds great.
Okay. See ya.
Wow.
I guess we're opening
for Pearl Jam.
-(screams)
-DANA: Oh, my God!
-Oh, my God! -Oh, my God,
I'm gonna meet Eddie Vedder!
(excited chatter)
How did this happen?
(live recording of "Alive"
by Pearl Jam playing)
♪ Oh, I ♪
♪ Oh, oh, I'm still alive ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, I ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, I... ♪
Hey, uh,
we're Lightning & Thunder.
Yeah, we're opening
for Pearl Jam.
Uh, okay. I'll check.
♪ ♪
♪ Mm... ♪
(quiet chatter)
(song ends)
Whoa, I always wanted one
of those Everly Brother Gibsons
with the wraparound pick guard.
-Yeah.
-It's a beaut.
Yeah, uh, Neil plays
one of these, right?
Mostly uses the Ovation
acoustics, but, uh...
-Yeah.
-You, uh... you on the tour?
Uh, me and my wife here,
we're, uh...
You're the Pearl Jam guy.
We-we talked on the phone.
I'm-I'm Eddie.
Eddie. That's right. Hey.
Thanks for this.
Um, Eddie, I'm, uh...
just a little worried
your crowd may not dig
my kind of show.
I-I don't get a lot
of mosh pits, you know?
There are no rules, man.
Tony Bennett's opening
for the Red Hot Chili Peppers.
Tony Bennett?
Besides, who doesn't like
Neil Diamond, right?
Are you, uh... are you playing
"Holly Holy" tonight?
Uh, no, not for this crowd,
but, uh...
Hey.
You mind if I ask you a favor,
you know,
one musician to another?
-(applause, cheering)
-This is exciting.
DANA:
It's happening.
-It's happening.
-Okay, okay. All good.
They're ready.
(crowd shouting)
FAN:
Come on!
Holy shit.
(cheering)
If you've ever had a shot,
pal, this is it.
(crowd shouting, whooping)
FAN:
Eddie, I love you!
ANNOUNCER:
Please welcome to the stage
Milwaukee's own
Lightning & Thunder.
(cheering and applause)
Hello, Milwaukee!
-That's great. The costumes
look great. -Yeah, yeah.
(playing Neil Diamond's
"Forever in Blue Jeans")
Come on, kids!
(clapping rhythmically)
Yeah.
Very big for them.
MIKE:
You know the words. Come on.
♪ Money talks ♪
♪ It don't sing and dance
and it don't walk ♪
♪ Long as I can have you
here with me ♪
♪ I'd much rather be
forever in blue jeans ♪
♪ Honey's sweet ♪
♪ It ain't nothin'
next to baby's treat ♪
♪ And if you pardon me,
I'd like to say ♪
♪ We'd do okay ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans ♪
Give it up for Eddie Vedder!
♪ Maybe tonight ♪
(cheering)
♪ Maybe tonight by the fire ♪
♪ All alone, you and I ♪
♪ Nothing around
but the sound of my heart ♪
♪ And your sighs ♪
-Come on, Milwaukee!
-(cheering)
♪ Money talks ♪
♪ But it don't sing and dance
and it don't walk ♪
♪ As long as I can have you
here with me ♪
♪ I'd much rather be ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans, babe ♪
♪ And honey's sweet ♪
♪ It ain't nothin'
next to baby's treat ♪
♪ If you pardon me,
I'd like to say ♪
♪ We'd do okay ♪
-♪ Forever in blue jeans ♪
-I love you, Eddie!
Eddie Vedder!
Lightning & Thunder, baby!
-It was like...
-Oh, my God.
-...he wanted to keep going.
-He was so cute, too.
But that audience,
they were just, like...
-(laughing)
-You look so good.
Oh!
(laughing)
(growling playfully)
♪ Money talks ♪
♪ But it don't sing and dance
and it don't walk ♪
♪ As long as I can have you
here with me ♪
♪ I'd much rather be ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans, babe. ♪
(song ends)
Zoo... ming in.
Zoo... ming out.
♪ ♪
DANA:
Hasn't hit our house yet.
And Rachel's fixing
her boyfriend's car.
-We were just changing the oil.
-She's not fixing it.
I know how to do it.
She just wanted to show me.
(engine starts)
♪ ♪
Everybody on the block
has flowers and bushes,
and then you look at this,
and we have nothing,
so I want flowers
and color and beauty.
Look at that.
Four shows a week
at the Shawano Casino,
two shows on Saturday.
Two shows on Saturday!
"As seen with Pearl Jam."
We're in the big time.
DANA:
Hey, Papa, how you doing?
How am I doing? I'm huge!
(blows sharply)
All right.
Which way are you facing?
Over here? Where do you want me?
In the corner? Over here?
That-that...
I think that's good.
All right.
Are you gonna put on some pants?
Nah. Shoot me from the waist up.
(chuckles)
All right.
Tell me when you're ready.
I'm ready when you are.
All right, this is
a prerecorded message
to be played on July 28th.
Hello. My name is Mike,
and I'm an alcoholic.
That's the part where
you all say, "Hello, Mike."
-Hello, Mike. (laughs)
-Hello.
Very good.
Uh, today is, uh, my 21st...
(whistles) sober birthday,
and, uh, I won't be able
to be there with you today
because I'll be playing my
new gig at the Shawano Casino,
but, uh, I thought maybe,
even though I can't be there,
I would sing you my song
just to...
well, just to let you all know
how important you all are to me.
♪ This is not a sad song ♪
♪ A sad song to sing
when you're alone ♪
Oh, no.
♪ In a way, it's a glad song ♪
♪ Yeah, a glad song ♪
♪ A simple song that simply
seems to make you feel good ♪
♪ When you sing along ♪
(strumming "Song Sung Blue")
(jet engine blaring)
♪ Song sung blue ♪
-♪ Everybody... ♪
-(engine revving)
(song stops abruptly)
(soft, high-pitched ringing)
♪ ♪
Mom!
-Dana!
-Excuse me.
-Uh, where is Claire Sardina?
-Rachel!
-That's her daughter.
-RACHEL: What's going on?
-What happened?
-A car rode on top...
-(heavy, gasping breaths)
-What?
She was... she was gardening,
and a car rode on top of her.
DOCTOR:
Need to increase the pressure.
RACHEL:
Mom! (screams)
-What's going...
-MIKE: It's okay. It's okay.
What's going on?
Come here. Johnny, Johnny.
Take Dana to the waiting room.
Take him.
-Take him. Okay.
-Come on. -(Dana sobbing)
-Gonna be all right.
-RACHEL: Is she gonna die?
-She's gonna make it.
-Is she... You have to tell me.
-But we got to talk.
-Is she gonna die?
-We got to talk. Come here.
-What's going on?
Okay, listen to me.
Who's that guy
on the show you like?
Uh, the guy with the eyebrows.
-Uh...
-What are you...
-George, George.
-What are you talking about?
-Uh, the guy from ER.
-What does this h-have to do...
Uh, Clooney, Clooney.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
Okay, something's
about to go down,
and you and I are gonna
take care of it...
-No, I need to...
-...while they work on your ma.
Now, listen to me.
I got a jacked-up heart...
(takes deep, groaning breath)
I got a jacked-up heart,
I've had it for a long time,
and I think I'm having
a heart attack.
What?
You-you need to get a doctor.
No, no, no, no, no.
We're gonna do my plan.
It's gonna be okay.
Now, you listen.
Listen to me, Rachel, okay?
-(device whirring, beeping)
-So...
I am gonna pass out,
and when I do,
you're gonna jolt me back
just like George does.
-No.
-Now, remember how I showed you
how to jump a car?
This is just like that.
I've done it before.
You can do this.
You see that?
You're gonna hold that,
and you're gonna put
that one up here.
In your right hand, you're
gonna put that down here.
All right?
You can do this, Rachel.
-I can't do this, Mike.
-Now, after you hear the...
-I can't do this. No...
-After you hear the...
(breathing heavily, muttering)
After I...
after I hear the what?
(screams)
Mike!
(rapid beeping)
Lightning! Lightning!
Papa!
(beep, high-pitched whirring)
(rapid beeping)
-(grunts)
-(gasps)
(gasps)
(crickets chirping)
(sighs)
-(pained yelling)
-Claire!
-Baby, baby, hey.
-Oh, I think I'm okay.
Oh, God. Claire, what happened?
I just... I...
I just... I just forgot.
Oh.
(Claire breathing heavily)
God.
-(Claire sighs)
-Come on, baby.
Hold tight.
(Claire groaning softly)
(Mike speaks softly)
It's only been three weeks
since your accident.
It's gonna take time to adjust.
Those motor skills
can take control.
-I know. -Especially
in the middle of the night
-when you're not
completely awake. -I know.
I just don't want to dwell
on it and get stuck.
If I have to make adjustments,
I just want to make them
and move on.
And that day will come,
but you need to allow yourself
some time.
NURSE KETT:
Please understand, Mr. Sardina,
this isn't something that needs
to be paid in full today.
The old guy that lost control
and hit my wife with the car,
his family isn't able
to provide the settlement money
for another six months.
What am I supposed to do
in the meantime?
There's dismemberment insurance
that your wife can qualify for.
That should cover
a sizable portion of the cost.
(inhales deeply, sighs)
That's a different department,
but I'd be happy to put you
in touch with them.
-Mm-hmm.
-And we still need to bill
your insurance company.
(laughs) Insurance?
Miss, do you know any musicians?
We're broke as a joke.
CLAIRE:
Me and Mike, we started singing.
We were really cooking.
And I could see it,
like-like a way to pay my bills
and-and be able to say I...
"Look at me. I made it."
DOCTOR: Take one
every three to four hours
for the phantom pains.
I was so close.
Yeah, thanks, Doc. Thanks.
♪ ♪
(birds screeching)
(sighs)
(takes deep breath)
(groaning softly)
(sighs)
(sighs heavily)
-(knocking)
-RACHEL: Mom?
-It's Wednesday.
-Mm.
Your prosthetic therapy
is in half an hour.
-Okay?
-Yeah, hon, no.
I-I don't think I can do that.
Okay, fine. If-if you're
gonna cancel again,
how about you make the call?
'Cause they don't buy my lies,
-and I'm sick of doing it.
-You know what?
-Can you just give me a minute?
-Mom, we got to go.
We got to drive there
-and-and get you in the car.
-Rachel.
-And it's gonna take a second.
-Rach.
Rach, please,
just give me a minute.
All right, fine. Just hurry up.
(sighs)
-(knocking)
-(groans)
Give me a minute.
-(knocking)
-I said give me a minute!
(sighs)
(knocking)
Rachel.
Goddamn it, I...
Dinner's ready.
♪ ♪
(breathing deeply)
(sighs softly)
(groans softly)
(takes deep breath)
(exhales slowly)
(grunts softly)
(grunts)
RACHEL:
It's geometry, and I told him...
MIKE:
Oh, I'm good at geometry.
RACHEL:
I hate it. There's no point.
I don't understand
when I'm gonna use any of it.
And I told that to him.
I was like, "I don't..."
MIKE:
Oh, you don't use it ever.
The thing about it is...
Why do I want to learn that
if I'm not gonna use it?
-It's, like, problem solving.
-CLAIRE: Hey.
What happened to therapy?
Are you serious?
I mean, that was... that was
four hours ago, and you...
You know what, I'm-I'm not...
-I'm done.
-MIKE: Oh, honey, grab a seat.
-Come here. Come on.
-(sighs)
Come on, babe.
We, uh, got screwed
on the mashed potatoes.
We got gravy, just no potatoes.
Anyway...
So, uh, I don't know,
maybe we take
a little road trip
down to Six Flags.
Get some, uh...
get some sunshine, you know?
A little adventure?
I'm gonna have
a little extra money,
seeing as I, uh,
may have got a job.
Yeah.
You guys remember Cliff?
You know, Sex Machine?
Does James Brown?
He says he might have some work
for me down at this Thai joint.
Uh, they just need
a host for karaoke,
but, uh, he thought
I could fill in for him.
So, you're gonna play
Neil Diamond songs?
Uh, no.
I mean, maybe a few, but
it's more of a hosting thing.
Getting other people singing,
you know?
-DANA: Yeah.
-Karaoke.
You know, it's only temporary.
It's, uh...
you know, until your mother
and me can, uh...
Get back on our feet?
DR. DAVE:
How are things going at home?
Not.
DR. DAVE:
Hmm.
I know the band
has other gigs, but, uh,
maybe you and Claire can still
use that karaoke machine.
(sighs)
It's not about
the instrumentation.
It's just, she won't
get up out of bed.
It's these drugs she's on,
and...
her mind, it...
Now, what does a duo do
if one doesn't want to do
what the other's doing?
I believe in you, Mike.
I always have.
Now, open up here.
RANEE:
Do you sing anything current?
Anything contemporary pop
or just dad rock stuff?
Dad rock? Like...
She means like, you know,
Skynyrd, Creedence, Steely Dan.
-That type of thing.
-Oh, yeah.
I rock with those guys.
Yeah, I mean...
Sorry, are you saying
you don't want me
-to sing those songs or...
-RANEE: I'm not saying not to.
I just want to hear Aaliyah and
Alanis every once in a while.
Yeah, Monica, Mariah.
See, the thing is, uh,
I got more of a specified act,
like Sex Machine here.
I mean, past year, I'm known
for singing Neil Diamond music.
But he can sing any music.
Luther Vandross, Usher, Jodeci.
(speaking Thai)
...Neil Diamond?
(Dao speaking Thai)
Ah. "Soolaimon"?
"Soolaimon"?
You know "Soolaimon"?
Nobody knows "Soolaimon."
They only know "Sweet Caroline."
"America," "Cracklin' Rosie."
You sing "Play Me"?
Anytime.
Ah. Ah.
Ah.
(speaking Thai)
...Neil Diamond.
You do know
who Jodeci is, right?
Hmm.
You can do your Neil Diamond
thing on Wednesday nights,
host karaoke Friday,
Saturday and Sunday.
SEX MACHINE:
Yeah.
Boom.
Brown, Brown,
Brown, Brown, Brown.
Head of family.
Yeah, yeah.
All right.
Name something that people
shake before they use it.
-(buzzer beeping)
-Yes, sir?
(TV broadcast continues
indistinctly in distance)
(sighs)
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
(phone ringing)
Claire?
-(phone continues ringing)
-(TV continues)
-(liquid pouring in sink)
-Claire? Claire?
RICHARD DAWSON (over TV):
Tell me something that men do
better than women.
-(phone continues ringing)
-(TV continues)
As you were.
Oh, hey, Sister Anne.
Uh, no, this is Lightning,
her husband.
I mean Mike.
Uh...
Okay, yeah. No, sure. Tomorrow?
We... No, we can be there.
Uh, all right.
You have a good day, too.
Uh...
Why didn't you pick up
the phone?
Uh, that was Sister Anne.
She, uh...
she wants us to come in
for some kind of parent-teacher
thing tomorrow for Dana.
All right, I got to get ready
to go out.
Where are you going?
Uh, I got my night gig
at the Thai joint.
Been doing it for weeks now,
you space cadet.
Yeah.
I, uh...
I see the way you look at those
girls in the crowd, you know?
How they look back at you.
I'm not a fool.
Oh, yeah? You think I got
a little piece on the side
'cause I'm so young
and wealthy? Huh?
I used to think it was so cute
the way you'd take the scarf
and put it around
all those hussies and kiss 'em.
The scarf was a bit.
You know that.
Yeah, for Elvis,
not for Neil Diamond.
You just wanted
to kiss them, Mike.
You know, I really wish
these medications
would make up their mind.
Are you gonna be, like,
loopy and not give a shit,
or are you gonna be angry
and paranoid?
You know what?
My mom was right about you.
You're just a selfish
son of a bitch.
So why don't you go find
yourself a new girlfriend
and give her a new nickname!
You think you're the only one
that's hurting?
-Every day, I think about
the big adios. -Oh.
Every day!
-But I'm here trying! I'm here!
-(objects clattering)
You want to throw shit at me?
You ought to throw
something else!
-Goddamn it!
-(door slams)
-(breathing heavily)
-(Claire sobbing)
("I Am... I Said"
karaoke track playing)
♪ Did you ever read
about a frog ♪
♪ Who dreamed of being a king ♪
♪ And then became one? ♪
♪ Well, except for the names
and a few other changes ♪
♪ If you talk about me ♪
♪ The story is the same one ♪
SOMECHAI: ♪ But I got
an emptiness deep inside... ♪
Oh, sorry. We're closed.
Oh. That's my-my dad.
Ah, Lightning?
It's my mother's birthday.
She died of lung cancer.
Sad songs all night.
Right.
BOTH:
♪ "I am," I said ♪
♪ To no one there ♪
♪ And no one heard at all ♪
♪ Not even the chair ♪
♪ "I am," I cried ♪
SOMECHAI:
♪ "I am," said I. ♪
(song ends)
You know, I...
I talk to Rachel a lot.
Hmm.
Rachel says that you and Claire
have been fighting a lot more.
So...
-Are you drinking or...
-No.
I'm wondering if, uh, the ride
would be a little less bumpy
if I fell off the wagon.
-When was your last meeting?
-Angie, what are you doing?
You're my daughter.
You're not my sponsor.
Look, everybody tells me
to move on.
I'm the guy
that looks like Neil.
"Why do you need Claire?"
But they-they just don't get it.
I...
I love her, and I'm...
I'm losing her.
(takes deep breath)
Listen, just... (sighs)
Dad...
would you just please
go to a meeting?
Please?
Mm.
(muffled jet engine roaring)
♪ ♪
Mike?
(faintly):
Ladies and gentlemen.
(applause)
(intro to Patsy Cline's
"Sweet Dreams" playing)
♪ Sweet dreams ♪
♪ Of you ♪
♪ Every night ♪
♪ I go through ♪
♪ Why can't I forget you ♪
♪ And start my life anew ♪
♪ Instead of having
sweet dreams ♪
♪ About you? ♪
♪ Sweet dreams ♪
♪ Of you ♪
MIKE:
Claire. Honey.
Claire.
Claire, come on. Come on down.
-Mike.
-Come on, let's go.
♪ Come true ♪
-Claire.
-Mike, don't do this.
-Mike, you're embarrassing me.
-No, no.
-I am not stopping.
-This is not your show.
-No.
-This is... You're confused.
-This is embarrassing.
-Come on. Come on, baby.
Mike, I would never
do this to you.
-You're scaring everybody.
-No, no.
And you're gonna get
yourself hurt. Let's go.
-Mike, no.
-Let's go. Go.
-I am not going any... Mike.
-Come on. Come on!
-(grunts)
-(song stops)
(vehicle approaching)
CLAIRE:
No.
-No, no.
-Mom?
CLAIRE: What are you doing?
What are you all doing up here?
-It's okay. It's okay.
-What about the show?
-She's just tired. It's okay.
-RACHEL: Okay, we just...
Mom, we just are trying
to help you, Mom.
-CLAIRE: No, no.
-Okay? We just...
No, this is my show.
I'm up here. I'm up here, Mike!
Okay, come on. Let's go.
I'm not going to stop the show!
-Come on, let's go.
-Don't touch me.
You're not even
supposed to be up here.
-(sobbing): Stop it, Mike!
-Baby, come here.
-Stop it. This is my show.
-Baby, come here. Come here.
-CLAIRE: This is my show!
-It's okay. It's okay.
Mike's got it, okay?
-(sobbing): Help me.
-RACHEL: He'll figure it out.
-It's all right. It's okay.
-DANA (crying): Mom.
(indistinct chatter)
NURSE: There's a 72-hour
observation period
for all voluntary patients.
A mental health professional
will assess her condition
and determine the course of
treatment and length of stay.
And if you could just fill out
the medication
she's currently taking
or anything she'll need
over the next three weeks.
I...
I know I'm a...
I'm a stranger to you,
but what I could really use...
...right now is...
is for you to just tell me I'm
doing the right thing for...
(breath trembles)
...for her.
We're gonna take
really good care of her,
make sure she gets
what she needs, okay?
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
(chuckles)
(grunts)
(softly):
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
(Claire sniffles)
(smacks lips) Oh, Mike.
I don't think we've been apart
more than a day
since we've been married.
(inhales)
It's okay.
-(softly): Okay. Okay.
-It's okay.
(takes deep breath)
CLAIRE:
Okay.
Thank you.
(sighs)
("O Holy Night" by Neil Diamond
playing)
(sniffs, sighs)
Right through there.
(Claire breathing deeply)
NEIL DIAMOND:
♪ O holy night ♪
♪ The stars are
brightly shining ♪
♪ It is the night ♪
♪ Of our dear Savior's
birth... ♪
Hey. Um... (clears throat)
I was wondering if I could
speak to the manager
or the guy who, um...
who does the hiring.
My radiator is hissing.
I'm trying to get a job here.
Yeah, well, I'm trying
to get to my job.
Being that I'm the only one
that has one here.
Uh, listen, I-I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. God.
-(groans)
-(distant train whistle blows)
(sighs)
-(hood latch clicks)
-All right.
Here you go.
Here you go. Hold this.
Just pour it in.
-But there's a leak.
-Yeah.
It'll fix it. Just do it.
It's got, uh, like,
little metal particles in it
that, uh, heat up
while the car is running.
And then it melts into the leak,
welds it closed.
-Slow, slow, slow.
-Yeah. (sniffs)
I get it.
There's people in this world
that get new shit,
and then there's people like us
just patching up broken shit.
I... I know this
has been hard for you.
Somewhere along the way,
I got put in charge
of everyone's problems.
I worry about my mother.
I worry about Dana.
(scoffs, sniffles)
Every time you touch your chest,
I worry about you.
I don't want you worrying,
and trust me,
this thing with your mother
is gonna get better.
I'm pregnant.
(Rachel takes deep,
shaky breath)
Oh. Okay.
Uh... uh, when?
Like...
four months ago.
Four months?
Oh, my God.
How did we miss this?
Because you're all crazy.
I mean, I'm-I'm huge.
How can you not see?
We all put on some pounds.
I just thought it was
a family phase. It's...
Uh, here. Give me that.
Uh, is it the guy you were...
No, that's over.
He can't be counted on.
And...
(crying):
I guess neither can I.
-Aw, baby. Baby, baby.
-(crying continues)
(Rachel sniffles)
Okay.
So we got this thing
in the Marines.
It's called a SMEAC, all right?
Stands for "situation,"
"mission," "execution,"
"administration" and "command."
It's a way to break down
a problem real simple.
Okay.
So, what's the situation?
-I'm knocked up.
-Okay. Okay.
So, what's the mission?
What do you want to do about it?
I want to give it to a couple
that wants to have a baby.
Okay, so that's the mission.
Okay. Now you got to execute.
You got to have the kid.
I already called the
Adoption Information Center,
and there's a potential couple
that could assist
in medical bills and all that.
Okay, so you already took care
of the "A" for administration.
That just leaves command.
So, who do you want to be
in charge of all this,
you know, helping you?
(voice shaking):
My mom.
(sighs)
Whenever Mike would run off
to his AA meetings, I...
I was always
pretty ugly about it.
Like, why can't you just
deal with your problems
without all the talking?
Mike can talk.
And I can talk, too,
and I talk a lot.
Sometimes I talk so much
I don't even know
what I'm saying half the time.
Yeah, and the thoughts,
they just, like,
go around in my head.
Spin around all the time.
That's where the singing helped.
And something happened when I...
would sing Patsy Cline songs,
like...
Like, I'd...
just disappear, you know?
In the music.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'd just...
disappear.
Yeah.
I mean, the accident
took my leg,
but I shouldn't have let it
take my singing away.
That's mine.
All mine.
(jet engine whirring)
(jet engine continues
whirring louder)
(whirring fades in distance)
Good night, Mom.
Mm, good night, sweetheart.
-Love you.
-Okay. Love you, too.
MIKE:
Good night, kiddo.
-Love you.
-DANA: Love you.
-Good night.
-Night.
(dog barking in distance)
I made a pot of coffee.
You want some?
No, thank you.
You want to watch a show?
I don't know.
Unless you do.
When do you go back to work?
I start back
at the shop tomorrow.
Well, what about karaoke?
Claire, we-we just got home.
I'm tired.
I-I'm just asking
a question, Mike.
No, no, you're getting ready
to argue.
And, you know, I just
don't know what's okay to say
and not to say
since you went to that place.
Well, if you have any questions,
I can answer them for you.
I...
I didn't get a lobotomy.
Not yet.
Well...
Well, I'm not doing
the karaoke thing
'cause, uh, I'm, uh...
well, I'm not doing
Lightning anymore.
That's o... that's over.
(choking up):
Lightning is, uh...
It's just nothing without you.
It's...
If you're not gonna be there
with me, I got no...
I got...
I got no song to sing. I got...
I got nothing.
♪ ♪
(quietly):
Honey. Oh, Mike.
-It's okay.
-(sobbing)
Oh, honey. Breathe, honey.
(sighs) I-I...
I've been doing
a lot of talking, you know,
-like you do at your meetings.
-Yeah.
And I've been figuring
things out in my head.
I think that the struggle
with my prosthetic...
I think it was more
in my head than my leg.
I felt hurt and-and-and ugly.
(Mike sniffles)
And, like, I had all this anger
inside of me and fear,
and it just cracked.
Now, look,
the folks at the hospital,
they talk about having
an emotional catharsis.
It's like where you let
everything go
and just move forward.
(Mike takes deep breath)
I don't think I've had that yet,
'cause everything still feels
very scary for me.
You know, walking and standing.
Singing.
But maybe if you're
there with me...
...I can have that catharsis.
("Holly Holy"
karaoke track playing)
(sniffles) Okay.
♪ Holly holy... ♪
Thank y'all for coming out here
tonight to Charm Thai.
Uh, we got a great night
here for you,
and don't forget, we, uh...
we do karaoke night
on Friday night,
Saturday night, Sunday night.
I've seen you here.
It's a lot of fun.
And, uh, well, there's also
the all-you-can-eat buffet
Monday to Friday.
But, uh, tonight
I got something, uh...
Wow, we got something special.
My name is Lightning.
This is my lovely wife Thunder.
And tonight,
we're gonna sing for you.
BOTH:
♪ Holly holy ♪
♪ Holly holy dream ♪
♪ Wanting only you ♪
He's good.
♪ And she comes ♪
♪ And I run ♪
♪ Just like the wind will ♪
♪ Holly holy ♪
-♪ Sing ♪
-♪ Sing a song ♪
♪ Sing ♪
♪ Sing a song of songs ♪
-♪ Sing ♪
-♪ Sing it out ♪
-♪ Sing it strong ♪
-♪ Sing, sing ♪
♪ Sing, sing, yeah... ♪
Nice. Nice, baby.
You're doing great.
(bicycle bell jingles)
♪ Call the sun
in the dead of the night ♪
-♪ Call the sun ♪
-♪ And the sun's gonna rise ♪
♪ In the sky... ♪
-Does it hurt?
-Yeah.
Okay.
♪ Touch a man
who can't walk upright ♪
-♪ Touch a man ♪
-♪ And that lame man ♪
♪ He's gonna fly ♪
-Why don't we stop?
-Okay.
-We stop?
-No, let's keep going.
-You sure?
-One more block. Yep.
-♪ And I fly ♪
-♪ Fly ♪
♪ Holly holy love ♪
♪ Take the lonely child ♪
♪ And the seed ♪
♪ Let it be filled
with tomorrow ♪
♪ Holly holy ♪
-♪ Sing ♪
-The words of Neil Diamond
bid you to make
a beautiful noise, Charm Thai.
♪ Sing ♪
-Are you ready to sing?
-(scattered applause, cheering)
Are you ready to sing?
-Yes!
-♪ Sing ♪
-Are you ready to sing?
-Yes!
Come on!
-♪ Sing a song ♪
-♪ Sing ♪
♪ Sing ♪
-♪ Sing, sing ♪
-Clap your hands with me.
-Come on!
-♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
Somechai, take the mic.
♪ Call the sun
in the dead of the night ♪
-♪ Call the sun ♪
-♪ And the sun ♪
♪ Gonna rise in the sky ♪
(laughing)
♪ Touch a man
who can't walk upright ♪
-♪ Touch a man ♪
-♪ And that lame man ♪
♪ He gonna fly ♪
-♪ And I fly, yeah ♪
-♪ Fly ♪
-♪ And I fly ♪
♪ Holly holy dream ♪
♪ Dream of only you ♪
♪ Holly holy sun ♪
♪ Holly holy rain ♪
♪ Holly holy love. ♪
(song ends)
(birds chirping)
(jet engine blaring)
(Claire screams)
Claire.
Babe, baby, you all right?
(breathing shakily)
(grunts unsteadily, sniffs)
I... I-I don't know
what happened.
I just... I lost control.
(Claire laughing)
I-I hope you're ok...
(laughing)
I... I...
I-I mean, don't you see?
(laughing): Lightning can
strike the same place twice.
(sighing):
Oh. Oh.
It's-it's okay.
I just... (laughs)
(beeping, whirring)
CLAIRE:
Look. All this music.
All this life.
And here's my accident.
-Mm-hmm.
-And then...
-nothing.
-MIKE: I see. I see.
What-what are you getting at?
I want these boxes
filled up again.
Bad things happen over and over.
And I just want to sing,
and I want to shine
before another car runs into me.
(laughing):
The car's not gonna run in...
Oh, God, it's like
they're aiming for me, Mike.
Come on.
I am not afraid anymore.
I want to be Thunder again.
♪ ♪
I know, I know...
I've been a little out of it
and I'm a little rusty,
but I'm here to be mom again
and a wife and a partner.
So, you know, what have I
missed these last few months?
What do I need to know?
You want to tell her or me?
(band playing intro to
Neil Diamond's "I'm a Believer")
And then slight stretch...
MIKE:
♪ I thought love was ♪
♪ Only true in fairy tales ♪
♪ Meant for someone else
but not for me ♪
(Rachel chuckling)
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Love was out to get me ♪
CLAIRE:
♪ Na-na-na, na-na... ♪
-Hi.
-NEIGHBOR: Morning, Claire.
MIKE: ♪ Disappointment haunted
all my dreams... ♪
-One, two, three, four, five.
-(Rachel straining)
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, he's coming.
♪ Not a trace... ♪
-Hi. Aw.
-Hi.
-♪ I'm in love ♪
-(quiet chatter)
CLAIRE:
♪ Mmm ♪
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ And I'm a believer ♪
♪ I couldn't leave her
if I tried ♪
-MIKE: Hey!
-(others whooping, hollering)
(indistinct, lively chatter)
(laughter)
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Love was out to get me ♪
CLAIRE:
♪ Do-da, da-da ♪
MIKE:
♪ That's the way it seemed ♪
CLAIRE:
♪ Do-da, da-da ♪
MIKE: ♪ Disappointment haunted
all my dreams ♪
(lively, excited chatter)
♪ Then I saw her face ♪
♪ Now I'm a believer ♪
♪ And not a trace ♪
♪ Of doubt in my mind ♪
-MIKE: ♪ I'm in love ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Mmm ♪
MIKE:
♪ And I'm a believer ♪
♪ I couldn't leave her
if I tried ♪
(cheering)
We're here today
joined by two local legends
staging the comeback
of their careers.
The universe sent two cars
to kill me,
uh, but I'm still standing,
even if it's on one leg.
(both laugh)
-♪ I'm in love ♪
-♪ Mmm ♪
♪ And I'm a believer ♪
♪ I couldn't leave her
if I tried. ♪
Yes!
-(cheering)
-(song ends)
I am a believer!
MARK:
Mike, Claire,
I want you to meet
my friend Buddy Holmes.
-Hey. -He's event coordinator
here at the Ritz.
-Hi.
-Buddy.
-Thank you both for coming.
-Claire.
You've been getting a lot
of press with your comeback.
Yeah, we never really left.
That's why I wanted to talk
to you about playing here.
Uh...
Oh, are we gonna open
for Pearl Jam again?
BUDDY:
No, you'd be the headliner.
It'd be on a Wednesday night
three weeks from now.
That'll give us just enough time
to get the word out,
sell some tickets.
Uh, sorry, you expect us to
fill this place on a Wednesday?
Oh, we'll make it work, Mike.
We'll make it work.
We know what you mean
to Milwaukee.
MIKE:
Hey, dreaming it is one thing,
but, you know,
we're not fools, Buddy.
MARK:
Mike, don't you know
what's happening in three weeks
on a Wednesday night?
-What? What? What's happening?
-Neil Diamond.
Neil Diamond.
He's playing a sold-out show
at the Wisconsin Center Arena.
We want to be
the counterprogramming
to that event.
Those who can't see Neil Diamond
see the next best thing.
Could we just take a second?
One moment.
Babe, I don't know
if we're ready for this.
-Oh.
-I mean...
I think you are.
I know I am.
(Mike sighs)
We're gonna need a choir.
("Forever in Blue Jeans"
instrumental playing)
Sex Machine is the
choir director at his church.
Great, and timpani.
You know, the big drums?
What would you need timpani for?
(scoffs)
I'll get the timpani, Mike.
I'll get the timpani.
Especially because
we're opening with "Soolaimon."
"Solomon"?
TOM and DR. DAVE:
"Soolaimon."
Okay, so remember
Rachel's gonna pick us up,
but I think I want to go
with Johnny to get
-a head start on my hair.
-Are you nervous?
No, actually, I'm not.
But maybe I will right before
the show. What about you?
I just hope people come, babe.
(vehicle doors closing)
-DR. DAVE: Hey.
-TOM: Mike!
-Oh, hey.
-DR. DAVE: Go ahead. You talk.
Okay, okay, okay.
I know the event coordinator
at the Wisconsin Center.
He was at your wedding.
You know, big guy.
-He had a big red beard.
-Good Lord.
Mike, you are going to meet
Neil Diamond tonight.
-I-I was gonna get to that.
-(Claire gasps)
Oh, my God.
-What do you mean?
-What?
He's gonna meet the two of you
at Lake Front Frozen Custard
after the show.
He's gonna drop in with his bus.
He loves their frozen custard.
What are you gonna say
to him, Dad?
Hopefully nothing dumb.
Oh, no, don't be silly.
It's just two musicians
after their show.
Uh, both sold-out shows.
We're sold out?
-It sold out? Sold out?
-DR. DAVE: Sold out.
Yeah, we sold out.
(excited laughter)
Now I'm nervous.
DR. DAVE:
This is a huge win for you.
You earned this, Mike.
You earned it.
(crying):
He did. I'm so happy.
-Are you crying?
-I'm just so happy.
Are you crying? I love you.
-I'm so happy for you.
-Come here.
I'm so happy, too.
All right, get out of here.
Go, go, go.
-We'll see you over there.
-I'll-I'll see you there.
-I'm going with Rachel.
-Congratulations.
-Okay. Okay.
-This is gonna be great.
DR. DAVE:
Come on, we've got things to do.
-TOM: Why do you do that?
-Oh, my...
(Dr. Dave and Tom continue
chatting indistinctly)
MIKE:
Mr. Diamond...
Or Neil. Can I...
Can I call you Neil?
You know, there's a certain way
that you sing "touching."
I mean, you must know
what I mean.
Of course you know
what I mean. It's you.
♪ Touching me, touching you. ♪
It's so good. I mean, it's just
a small thing, but, like...
♪ Touching... ♪ (gasps)
Oh!
(weak, gasping breaths)
(groaning)
♪ ♪
(breathing heavily, grunting)
(panting):
Okay.
(hisses in pain)
Papa?
I'm getting dressed.
Uh, Angelina had some friends
she wanted to bring tonight,
but I guess it's sold out.
MIKE:
Uh, yeah, no, no. We, uh...
We've got that handled.
(groans)
Hey, I'm going to, uh...
I'm gonna meet Neil Diamond
tonight.
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
Wow. (laughs)
First, Eddie Vedder,
and now Neil Diamond.
You think you could hook me up
with Christian Slater?
(chuckles)
Papa?
(knocking)
Papa, you all right?
I'm huge, baby.
(indistinct chatter)
(musicians playing scales,
tuning instruments)
(inhales sharply)
Hey, Dad.
Hey, darling.
Oh, I'm so glad you're here.
Oh, I wouldn't miss this.
(chuckles)
MIKE: Grandma.
Hey, uh, just to warn you,
the seats we got reserved
are right up front.
-It may get loud.
-I'm half deaf anyway,
so I'll be fine.
Have a great show tonight, Mike.
-Thanks. -Okay, Lightning,
five minutes. Five minutes!
-Places, everybody, places!
-MIKE: Ooh, five minutes. Okay.
-All right.
-Hey. Wait, give me a kiss.
-Give me a kiss.
-Oh, all right.
So, any last-minute
words of advice
or encouragement
from my two girls?
Yeah.
Play "Sweet Caroline," okay?
(chuckles)
(sighs)
You two always know what to do.
You're not afraid
of the lift at all?
Oh, no, I just
got to stand there.
-CLAIRE: Okay.
-MIKE: Okay.
CLAIRE:
Mm.
Hey, Claire.
I can't thank Neil
'cause every thank-you I got
belongs to you, doll.
You're my August Night,
you're my "September Morn,"
you're my "Heartlight,"
and you're my
"Cracklin' Rosie," you got me?
♪ ♪
I'll see you onstage.
(takes deep breath)
(groans)
(crowd cheering)
(band playing upbeat intro)
(cheering and applause)
-(whooping)
-(excited chatter)
Huh!
-♪ I woke up this morning ♪
-Yeah!
♪ And the sun
was shining bright ♪
♪ I said,
I woke up this morning ♪
-Yeah!
-♪ And the sun ♪
♪ Was shining bright ♪
-Whoo!
-Yeah!
♪ I called the weatherman,
I said, "Weatherman ♪
♪ "How can there be no rain
when all I see and hear is ♪
♪ Lightning & Thunder?" ♪
(playing intro to "Soolaimon")
-Yes!
-Cue back light.
Cue back light. Reel it in.
There you go. Bring it up.
(cheering swells)
Good evening, Milwaukee!
Go, Mom!
CLAIRE:
Welcome to those who yearn
to dance in the glow of glory.
Our friends, our fans, family,
those who could not get
Neil Diamond tickets.
(cheering)
Stand by.
CLAIRE:
Because tonight, we make
our own beautiful noise.
Cue the lift.
(cheering)
Yes, Dad!
Cue the fans.
♪ Come here, come say ♪
♪ Ride ♪
♪ On the night ♪
♪ Sun become day ♪
♪ Day ♪
♪ Shall provide ♪
♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
♪ Soolai, soolai, soolaimon ♪
♪ God of my want, want, want ♪
♪ Lord of my need, need, need ♪
♪ Leading me on, on, on ♪
♪ On to my woman,
she dance for the sun ♪
♪ Lord of my day, day, day ♪
♪ God of my night,
night, night ♪
♪ Seek for the way, way, way ♪
♪ Taking me home ♪
♪ She callin' ♪
I love you, Milwaukee!
(cheering)
♪ Bring home my name ♪
♪ On ♪
♪ The wings of a flea ♪
♪ Wind in the plains ♪
♪ Dance ♪
♪ Once for me ♪
♪ Soo, soolaimon ♪
♪ Soolai, soolai, soolaimon ♪
You know the words!
Let me hear you!
♪ God of my want, want, want ♪
♪ Lord of my need, need, need ♪
♪ Leading me on, on, on ♪
♪ On to my woman,
she dance for the sun ♪
♪ God of my day, day, day ♪
♪ Lord of my night,
night, night ♪
♪ Seek for the way, way, way ♪
♪ Taking me home ♪
-(high-pitched ringing)
-(muffled cheering)
(breathing heavily)
(whispering):
Help me. Help me.
Help me, brothers and sisters,
and the itty-bitty children,
Black and white,
rich and poor, great and small.
All God's children, sing,
"Hallelujah!"
(cheering)
CLAIRE and CHOIR:
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Halle, hallelujah ♪
♪ Halle, hallelujah... ♪
And the good Lord
gave us two hands.
One hand for the giving,
one hand for the taking.
And when your brother is hungry
and he ain't got what to eat,
and when he is tired and he
ain't got no place to sleep,
and when his heart is aching
and it is full of pain,
who's gonna cry with him,
brothers?
Who's gonna cry with him?
You take your hand,
you put it out to him
and you say to him,
"That's what it's there for."
♪ Take my hand, sweet Lord ♪
♪ Walk with me this day ♪
♪ In my heart I know ♪
♪ I will never stray ♪
♪ Halle, halle, halle, halle ♪
♪ Halle, halle, halle ♪
♪ It's Love, Brother Love say ♪
♪ Brother Love's
Travelling Salvation Show ♪
♪ Pack up the babies
and grab the old ladies ♪
♪ And everyone goes,
everyone knows ♪
♪ Brother Love's show ♪
♪ God of my want ♪
♪ Oh, God of my want ♪
♪ Lord of my need ♪
♪ Hey, the Lord of my need ♪
♪ Taking me home ♪
♪ Take me home... ♪
(song ends)
(cheering and applause)
(band playing intro
to "Sweet Caroline")
Yeah!
-They're back. They're back.
-Yeah.
♪ ♪
Do you remember when we saw
Springsteen in-in East Troy?
(gasps)
Oh, my God, you saw Bruce?
-I love him so much.
-ANGELINA: Where was that?
-Where was that?
-MIKE: Uh,
Alpine Valley Music Theater.
You were a kid in grade school.
But he played
for like two extra hours
and everyone was freaking out
and dancing on the lawn.
That was this. That was this.
(laughs) Me and Bruce.
You know, I got to say--
and I don't mean any disrespect
to Mr. Eddie Vedder...
Uh-oh. Be careful, Mom.
I think tonight we were
just as big as Pearl Jam.
Well, it's a whole nother crowd.
No, I got to say, our fans are
just as big and just as loud.
-Oh.
-(crowd clamoring nearby)
Word must have got out, Papa.
Oh, my God! (screams excitedly)
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
(whooping, whistling)
♪ Good times never
seemed so good... ♪
Aw. Are you good? Are you ready?
I'm huge, baby.
♪ To believe
they never would... ♪
Hi.
-(clamoring)
-CLAIRE: Hi.
TOM:
Claire. Claire.
Neil just finished his show.
He's on the bus.
-Oh, great.
-He's on his way.
Come on, Mike. Come on.
Come on.
Mike, come on.
Mike?
Mike.
Mike. Mike.
Mike. Mike. Mike.
Mike!
(song stops abruptly)
♪ ♪
This is hard.
I'm not good
at writing speeches.
But...
I guess I've never written one.
So it'll be perfect.
"You two always know
what to do."
(chuckles softly)
Why did he say that?
It's like...
I feel like I don't know
how to do anything.
(chuckles)
Except patch
a leaky car radiator.
(laughs)
(both laughing)
Come here.
(takes deep breath)
Maybe he wasn't wrong about us.
He wasn't.
(chuckles softly)
DANA:
You look nice.
Aw, thank you.
Sometimes I forget
about your leg.
Yeah.
Me, too, and then I take a step.
You don't have to sing today.
Somebody else can do it
if it's too much for you.
I know.
But it's something I have to do.
Not just for Mike.
♪ ♪
(clears throat)
Hi.
(voice breaking):
This is gonna be hard.
(takes deep breath)
Every time, um,
we would play a gig,
everyone wants to hear
"Sweet Caroline," and...
(laughing):
Mike would get so mad.
(guests laughing)
He believed there was
so much more
to Neil Diamond's music.
So many more songs.
And there was more to Mike
than being Lightning.
Uh, he was a soldier...
...a father...
...a friend.
He was the love of my life.
And really, I'm standing here
because of him.
So...
...in his honor,
I'm gonna get myself
together... (chuckles)
(guests laugh softly)
...and I'm gonna sing a song.
A Neil Diamond song
that's not as well-known
as "Sweet Caroline."
(takes deep breath)
But Mike...
It's beautiful.
(playing intro to
"I've Been This Way Before")
♪ I've seen the light ♪
♪ And I've seen the flame ♪
♪ And I've seen ♪
♪ Your eyes before ♪
♪ And I'm sure to see
your eyes again ♪
♪ Once again ♪
♪ For I've been released ♪
♪ And I've been regained ♪
♪ And I've sung ♪
♪ My song before ♪
♪ And I'm sure to sing
my song again ♪
♪ Once again ♪
♪ Some people got to laugh ♪
♪ Some people got to cry ♪
♪ Some people ♪
♪ Got to make it through ♪
♪ By never wondering ♪
♪ Why ♪
♪ And some people got to sing ♪
♪ And some people got to sigh ♪
♪ Some people ♪
♪ Never see the light ♪
♪ Until the day ♪
♪ They die ♪
♪ But I've been released ♪
♪ And I've been regained ♪
♪ And I've been ♪
♪ This way before ♪
♪ And I'm sure to be
this way again ♪
♪ Once again ♪
♪ One more time again ♪
♪ Just one more time. ♪
(song ends)
(birds chirping)
(wrench clicking)
(whirring)
-MIKE (on video): All right.
-(strumming guitar on video)
Dana, you all right? You got it?
-DANA (on video): I got you.
-You sure?
-(Dana giggling)
-Are you sure?
-Positive.
-Are you positive?
-(chuckles) I'm positive.
-Have you got me?
-(Dana laughing)
-Have you got me, Dana?
-DANA: We got you.
-MIKE: I can see you.
-DANA: I can see you, too.
-MIKE: I got my eye on you.
DANA:
All right, we're rolling.
(Mike chuckling)
All right. Hey, everybody.
My name is Mike,
and I'm an alcoholic.
-Uh...
-Hello, Mike.
Today is my 22nd sober birthday,
but I can't be with you
here today
-because, uh...
-(burbling, beeping)
...well, we're getting ready
for our big comeback,
uh, Thunder and me,
and it's, uh...
it's real exciting and, uh...
You know what? Before I sing,
I just want to tell you
something.
We're all here doing
the best we can, right?
Very, very best.
And if we can just look out
for each other
and be strong
and above all be grateful,
maybe we can just...
I don't know,
we can turn things around,
we can make the world
a better place.
What do you say?
All right?
Anyway...
(strums guitar)
♪ This is not a sad song ♪
♪ A sad song to sing
when you're alone ♪
No, no.
♪ In a way, it's a glad song ♪
♪ Yeah, a glad song ♪
♪ A simple tune that simply
seems to make you feel good ♪
-Hey, Mom.
-♪ When you sing along ♪
(strumming intro
to "Sung Song Blue")
Come on. Sing along.
I know it's early.
(singing along):
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Everybody knows one ♪
"Every garden grows one."
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Every garden grows one ♪
All right. I'm ready.
♪ Me and you ♪
-Uh...
-♪ Are subject to ♪
♪ The blues now and then ♪
All clear.
♪ When you take the blues
and make a song ♪
♪ You sing them out again ♪
♪ You sing 'em out again ♪
I can hear you.
Sounds real good. Come on, now.
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Weeping like a willow ♪
"Sleeping on my pillow."
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Sleeping on my pillow ♪
It's a funny thing.
♪ Funny thing ♪
♪ But you can sing it
with a cry in your voice ♪
Right?
♪ And before you know it
get to feeling good ♪
Beauty and color.
♪ You simply got no choice ♪
♪ Song sung blue ♪
♪ Song sung blue. ♪
(song ends)
Thank you, and good night.
(band playing
"Crunchy Granola Suite")
MIKE:
♪ Mmm ♪
♪ I got a song been on my mind ♪
♪ And the tune can be sung
and the words all rhyme ♪
(Mike and Claire scatting
in harmony)
♪ Though it don't say much
and it won't offend ♪
♪ If you sing it at school ♪
♪ They're liable
to send you home ♪
♪ Never knowin'
what you're showin' ♪
♪ Think you're growin'
your own tea ♪
♪ Good Lordy ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ Let me hear that,
get me near that ♪
♪ Crunchy Granola Suite ♪
♪ Drop your shrink
and stop your drinkin' ♪
♪ Crunchy granola's neat ♪
♪ Sing it out ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ Heh, heh ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah. ♪
Come on!
(song ends)
("Holly Holy"
karaoke track playing)
CLAIRE:
♪ Holly holy eyes ♪
♪ Dream of only me ♪
♪ Where I am, what I am ♪
♪ What I believe in ♪
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Holly holy ♪
♪ Holly holy dream ♪
♪ Wanting only you ♪
MIKE:
♪ And she comes ♪
♪ And I run
just like the wind will ♪
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Holly holy ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Sing ♪
-MIKE: ♪ Sing a song ♪
-MIKE: ♪ Sing a song of songs ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Sing ♪
-MIKE: ♪ Sing it out ♪
-♪ Sing it strong ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Sing, sing ♪
♪ Sing, sing ♪
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Yeah ♪
MIKE: ♪ Call the sun
in the dead of the night ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Call the sun ♪
-MIKE: ♪ And the sun's gonna ♪
♪ Rise in the sky ♪
♪ Touch a man
who can't walk upright ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Touch a man ♪
-MIKE: ♪ And that lame man ♪
♪ He's gonna fly ♪
♪ And I fly ♪
CLAIRE:
♪ Fly ♪
-MIKE: ♪ And I fly ♪
-CLAIRE: ♪ Fly ♪
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Holly holy dream ♪
♪ Dream of only you ♪
♪ Holly holy sun ♪
♪ Holly holy rain ♪
♪ Holly holy love. ♪
(song ends)
(band playing
"Forever in Blue Jeans")
MIKE:
♪ Money talks ♪
♪ But it don't sing and dance
and it don't walk ♪
♪ Long as I can have you
here with me ♪
♪ I'd much rather be ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans ♪
♪ Honey's sweet ♪
♪ But it ain't nothin'
next to baby's treat ♪
♪ If you'll pardon me,
I'd like to say ♪
♪ We'd do okay ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans ♪
MIKE and CLAIRE:
♪ Maybe tonight ♪
♪ Maybe tonight by the fire ♪
♪ All alone, you and I ♪
♪ Nothing around
but the sound of my heart ♪
♪ And your sighs ♪
♪ Money talks ♪
♪ But it don't sing and dance
and it don't walk ♪
♪ As long as I can have you
here with me ♪
♪ I'd much rather be ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans, babe ♪
♪ Money talks ♪
♪ But it don't sing and dance
and it don't walk ♪
♪ As long as I can have you
here with me ♪
♪ I'd much rather be ♪
♪ Forever in blue jeans, babe. ♪
(song ends)